ZACK BORGES

Athens, Ga | <u>zackartborges@gmail.com</u> | 954-806-3516 github.com/zackartborges | https://www.linkedin.com/in/zack-borges/

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Innovative emerging software developer with a career driven mindset that is constantly learning and growing as a person as well as a developer. Communicate confidently with superiors, peers, and subordinates. Experience with full stack software development specializing in Ruby and JavaScript. Conversant in Spanish.

SKILLS

Technical: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Vue.js, React, Express, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, AWS, Amazon Web Services, Heroku, EC2, S3, Testing, Pair-Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, API's, Bootstrap, SEO, UI/UX design

EDUCATION

Actualize Coding Bootcamp | Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

2021

Learned the fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and learned how to effectively self-teach new technologies.

- Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schemas, and researched outside resources.
- Built and tested the backend, incorporating external API's
- Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes.

Georgia Southern University | Bachelor of Arts in Psychology

2019

PROJECTS

OurPack GitHub | Website

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Vue.js, localStorage, Node.js, Bcrypt, Axios, Heroku Engineered web app to allow for planning long-lasting backpacking treks

- Setup API routes to efficiently and correctly respond to front end requests.
- Coded to dynamically create, edit, and delete varying categories of backpacking gear.
- Implemented hashed passwords and JWT tokens to restrict access to verified users.

CorkBoard GitHub | Website-Pending

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, Vue.js, localStorage, Node.js, Bcrypt, Axios, ActionCable, Heroku

Built a peer-to-peer messenger web and mobile app to allow users to create a profile and add other users and send instant messages to one another.

- Utilized ActionCable, seamlessly integrating WebSockets into the application.
- Colla with a developer, utilizing GitHub branch best practices
- Deployed onto AWS using an EC2 Instance, S3, and RDS

Portfolio GitHub | Website

Technologies: : NuxtJS, VueJs, Vuetify, CSS Engineered portfolio website from scratch.

- Enhanced UX with a unique color scheme and readable font
- Utilized Vuetify UI components to ease development process

JavaScript Framework Tracker GitHub | Website

Technologies: Vanilla.js, HTML, Chart.js

Engineered a simple visualization of popular JavaScript frameworks according to GitHub repositories of each framework.

- Utilized Chart.js to provide a clean display of results
- Engineered an algorithm to efficiently fetch and display data from the GitHub API.

State Data Display GitHub | Website

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, VueJS, PostgreSQL, DataMaps

Provided a visual representation of state statistics

- Displayed data of each state using a clean and readable algorithm
- Migrated data from a CSV file containing data regarding each of the United States into a relational database.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Contractor | House Painting, Cabinet Installs, House Framing

Jan 2020 - Present

- Clarified with customers on specifications and requirements for home renovations, assessed the most efficient and productive path to take.
- Supervised and mentored teams of 3-4 house painters, ensuring proficiency and quality.
- Demonstrated professional attitude and results for every job.

Security Professional | Victory North Entertainment Venue

Oct 2019 - Jan 2020

- Monitored safety of patrons before, during, and after events. Quickly responded to issues and disturbances and defused tensions or removed patrons as needed, with care and protection for all involved.
- Sanitized and refreshed the venue at the end of every shift

Deli Clerk | Publix Deli

Feb 2017 – Nov 2019

- Engaged customers using techniques that promoted sales
- Organized and sorted all food and beverage inventory in the department, maintaining quality and food safety standards.